A Guide to the Nancy Bondurant Jones Papers, 1909-2011 (bulk 1991-2007): SC 0192
Special Collections, Carrier Library, James Madison University
- Series 1: Subject Files, 1909-2010 (bulk 1991-2005)
  - UFO's, undated (Box 12, Folder 16)
  - Valiant Virginians, undated (Box 12, Folder 17)
  - VA Theaters, undated (Box 12, Folder 18)
  - VFH Views, 2008, 2009 (Box 12, Folder 19)
  - Violence, 1994 (Box 12, Folder 20)
  - Virginia: First in the Heart of the Nation, undated (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Virginia Historical Society, 1991, 1993-1995, 1998, 2008 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - VMRC, 2004, 2005, undated (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Walking Tours, 1994, undated (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Warren County High Schools, undated (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Wars - Vietnams' Notes, 1994, undated (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Watkins, Evelyn, 1994, undated (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Wayland, John Walter, undated (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Weather, 1990, 1993, undated (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - West Virginia, 1994 (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Working Women's Forum, 1999-2005, undated (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - Writers, 1990 (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - WWII, 2000, undated (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - WWII + 1940s, 1992, 1997, undated (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - WWII: Conscientious Objectors, 1992, 1994 (Box 13, Folder 15)
  - WWII: Diehl, Co. C., 2001, undated (Box 13, Folder 16)
  - WWII: German P.O.W.s: Wehrmacht Autumns, 2001, undated (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - WWII - P.O.W.s, 2001, undated (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Zenda - Al Jenkins, 2003-2005, 2008-2010, undated (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Zigler, 1990, undated (Box 14, Folder 4)
- Series 2: Personal Papers, 1979-2011 (bulk 1992-2007)
  Arranged chronologically and then alphabetically.
  Series 2: Personal Papers, 1979-2011 (bulk 1992-2007), contains papers relating to Jones's professional and personal involvements. These include annotated drafts of books and articles, documents relating to institutions such as the Sorensen Institute and the National League of American Pen Women, and speeches and interviews throughout the years. All folders with number titles, such as the 100s, 200s, etc, contain selections of Daily-News Record columns authored by Jones. Many full-length drafts of her books as well as documents relating to their publication are included. In addition, a resignation-like thank you letter from Jones to Dr. Carrier is included in General Correspondence, box 17, folder 1. Media items in this series include floppy disks containing Jones's articles and other written documents as well as cassette and microcassette tapes that mainly appear to be interviews that Jones conducted with Dr. Ronald E. Carrier, Lucille Smead, Harry Caplinger, and others.
  - Personal MISC + Medical, 1979-1982, undated (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Rockingham Construction Company, 1987-1989, undated (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Writing Lecture, 1989, 1995, 1996, undated (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Vita, 1990, 1992 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Cols. 1-99, 1990, undated (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Harrisonburg-Rockingham Retired Teachers' Association, 1991-1992, undated (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Personal Reminisces, 1991, undated (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Personal Papers for JMU, 1992-1994, 2003 (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Homespun, 1992-1995, undated (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Speeches, 1992-1995, 1998-2004, undated (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - 100s, circa 1993, undated (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - Lessons - ICL, 1993, 1994, undated (Box 15, Folder 12)
  - 200s, 1994-1996, undated (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Interviews, 1996, 1997, undated (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - 300s, 1996-1998, undated (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Working Women's Forum: Women of the Year 2001, 1997, 2001, 2003, undated (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - 400s, 1998-2000, undated (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Sorensen Institute, 1998-2002, undated (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Sorensen Institute 1, 1999-2006, undated (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - Sorensen Institute 2, 1999-2006, undated (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - General Correspondence, 2000-2005, undated (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Greater Madison, 2001-2005, undated (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Uncommon Women of the Commonwealth - Speech, 2001-2002, 2011, undated (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - 500s, 2001, undated (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Jeremy the wonderful/ Jeremias el curiosa, 2002, 2006-2008, undated (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Family Papers, Letters, etc, 2004, 2005, undated (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Working Women's Forum/ Getting to Know You, 2004, 2005, undated (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - Return Luck, 2004, undated (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - Speech for VA Writers + Contract w/ Community Foundation, 2004, undated (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - Yesteryear, 2005-2008, undated (Box 17, Folder 10)
  - Speeches - MISC, 2005-2009, undated (Box 17, Folder 11)
  - Photographs, 2006, 2007 (Box 17, Folder 12)
  - VMRC, 2006, undated (Box 17, Folder 13)
  - Farmer's and Merchant's Bank, 2007, undated (Box 17, Folder 14)
  - United Way, 2007, undated (Box 17, Folder 15)
  - Zenda, 2007, undated (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Zenda Talks, 2007, undated (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Wharton Aldhizer & Weaver, 2008, undated (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - National League of American Pen Women, 2009, undated (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - UVA Book Proposal, 2010, undated (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Articles, undated (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - Banking on the Future, undated (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - Creative Writing, undated (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - My Writing - MISC, undated (Box 18, Folder 9)
  - Seeking Permanence on the Landscape: A History of Zenda, 1869-1930, undated (Box 18, Folder 10)
  - Stationary, undated (Box 18, Folder 11)
  - Wampler, Charles, undated (Box 18, Folder 12)
  - WWII, undated (Box 18, Folder 13)
  - Zenda Draft, undated (Box 18, Folder 14)
  - Media (cassettes, floppy disks), 1997, undated (Box 19, Folder 1)